DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宫饭》
Drop your weapons now.
快放下武器
Back up and lie on your stomach.
退后 趴在地上别动
If you twitch a muscle, I'll kill her.
只要敢动一下 我就杀了她
Isn't she one of Shuro's retainers?
她不是修洛那群跟班里的 其中一个家伙吗？
Was she following us this whole time?
她一直在跟踪我们？
You.
至于你
Undo these spells.
快解除这咒语
Huh?
什么？
The spells I'm under!
我是叫你解除我身上的咒语！
Get to it!
快点！
W-What kind of spells are you under?
你被施了什么样的魔法？
Can't you tell by looking?
你看不出来？
You wield black magic, don't you?
你不是会用黑魔法吗？
At least clue me in on what they're cast on
至少要告诉我魔法是施在哪里
and what kind of magic they are.
还有是什么样的魔法
There are two types of spells on me.
我身上被施了两种咒语
One's on my neck.
一个在脖子上
And the other…
另外一个…
Huh?
什么？
Is all over my body.
则在我的全身
Is she a beast-man?
那是兽人吗？
Yeah.
是啊
I've seen one a long time ago.
我以前看过一次
An engineered beast-man.
那是人工制造的兽人
Apparently, they're made with black magic, mixing human and beast souls together.
我听说是用黑魔法 把人和动物的灵魂混在一起做成的
Fine. I'll do what I can.
知道了 我尽力而为
This…
这是…
looks like it's written in the Eastern script.
好像是用东方的语言写的
What kind of spells are they?
这是什么样的咒语？
Can't you tell by looking?
你用看的看不出来吗？
They activate when the spellcaster goes without touching them for a while.
这是一段时间内没有被施法者碰触 就会自行启动的咒术
Is the spellcaster the one called Maizuru?
施法者是那个叫舞鹤的人吗？
How much time do you have left?
还剩下多少时间？
What happens when you run out of time?
时限到了会发生什么事？
Who knows?
天晓得
You might want to hurry.
劝你动作快点喔
You don't want to die with me, do you?
你不想跟我一起死吧？
I'll let you go once you undo the spells.
只要你帮我解除这东西 我就会放你走
The writing is peculiar.
文字是东方特有的
But I have a feeling I can undo them.
不过我应该能解除
Hey, you brat.
喂 那个小鬼
Huh?
什么？
Fetch me something to eat.
给我拿些吃的过来
FIELD RATION PELLET
（兵粮丸）
When's the last time you had something to eat?
你最后一次吃饭是什么时候的事？
If you shovel it in that fast, you'll choke.
吃得那么急 小心噎到喔
Shut up.
啰嗦
I'll prepare something hot for you.
老夫煮点热腾腾的料理给你吃吧
Hey! Did I say you could move?
喂！不准乱动！
Whoa!
哇！
Don't underestimate--
你别瞧不起我…
You need something to moisten your throat.
你需要喝点东西润喉
I'll fix you something. That's all.
老夫只是去帮你准备汤品
If you try to feed me monsters, I'll kill you.
如果敢给我吃魔物 我就宰了你
Deal.
知道了
I'm pretty sure I picked up some mushrooms around where the Dryads were.
上次好像有在树精旁边捡些蘑菇回来
They're starting to sprout leg-like things.
是不是长出了像脚的东西？
Must be my imagination.
应该是老夫看错了
I'll set my pot on the magic circle,
将锅子放到魔法阵上
melt some butter, sauté some garlic,
加热融化黄油 爆香大蒜
and toss in the rice.
让白米下锅
Then I'll add the mushrooms and seasonings,
加入蘑菇和调味料
pour in some water, and let it stew for a bit.
加水炖煮一段时间
The fact that this is all I can make makes me feel useless and pathetic.
竟然只能煮出这点程度的汤 老夫真是无力 太丢人了
At any rate, I can't stand the idea of young ones going hungry.
无论如何 老夫就是 不能忍受年轻人挨饿
But at least,
至少啊
I can throw in some cheese.
要丢点芝士下去
It's done.
完成了
RISOTTO WITH MUSHROOMS FROM A GRAVEYARD AND CHEESE FROM ORCS
（从墓地采来的蘑菇 及半兽人给的芝士炖饭）
I'll put it here.
料理就放这儿了
You think I'd eat that?
谁稀罕吃那种东西啊？
This kid…
这孩子…
Her table manners
她的用餐礼仪
are terrible!
真糟糕！
Give me more!
我还要！
Is etiquette different in the East or something?
东方的用餐礼仪和我们这边相反吗？
We never saw Shuro eating like that.
我们以前也没看过 修洛吃饭吃成那样啊
She simply had a poor upbringing.
她单纯只是没教养而已
Guess that's unfamiliar to you.
我猜你应该很少看到这种人
-Huh?
-什么？
Why did you do that?
你刚才做了什么？
I hate mushrooms.
我讨厌吃蘑菇
She's picky!
她挑食！
This has never happened before.
从来没遇过这类型的人
Senshi…
先西…
Your spoon.
你的汤匙
Hold your spoon properly.
要用正确的方法拿汤匙
Hey!
喂！
If you come any closer, I'll kill you!
敢再靠近一步就杀了你！
Hold your spoon the right way and pick up what you threw on the floor.
正确拿好手中的汤匙 将你刚才丢到地上的食物捡起来
-What'd you say? -Hey!
-你说什么？ -等等！
Don't!
不行！
It's risky to move when I'm undoing your spell!
在解除咒语的途中乱动会有危险！
Hold your spoon like this.
汤匙是要这样握
W-Who cares how I hold it?
要你管！
This way is easier for me!
我这样子拿最顺手！
I'm not surprised.
也是啦
Having someone force you to hold a spoon in an unfamiliar way must be annoying.
被逼着用不习惯的方法拿餐具
However--
不过…
Senshi, behind you!
先西 小心后面…
Huh?
奇怪
I didn't feel anything.
没有砍到的感觉
Is this paper?
纸片？
Senshi, watch out!
先西 小心啊！
That's a carving knife, a type of knife used for cutting meat.
那是切肉刀 顾名思义 是一种用来切割肉类的菜刀
It's got a long, sharp blade that can look pretty intimidating,
刀身长而尖锐 光看就让人毛骨悚然
but it's thin and delicate.
但是薄而细致
If you wave it around like that, what do you think is going to happen?
要是那样使劲乱挥 你觉得会怎么样？
Senshi!
先西！
Just like that, you might not get the most out of your tool,
就会像这样 无法发挥出工具的能力
leaving yourself at a disadvantage.
可能让自己陷于不利的处境
Senshi!
先西！
Now, Laios!
趁现在 莱欧斯！
Are you hurt, cat girl?
你没有受伤吧？猫女孩
I'm sorry for giving you a fright.
抱歉让你吓到
However,
但是呢
there are right and wrong ways to hold a tool.
“为什么工具的拿法 会有对错之分？”
I want you to think about why that's the case.
希望你能想想这问题
And why you shouldn't move while a spell's being undone.
也要想想为什么解除魔法时不能动喔
If the spells had been nastier, who knows what might've happened.
如果咒语更棘手 就不晓得现在会是什么下场了
The food's gone cold.
料理都凉掉了
I'll reheat it quick.
老夫现在就去加热一下
So?
所以呢？
Why were you coming after us?
你为什么要跟着我们？
All this time, I've been looking for a way to break the curses on my body.
我一直在寻找 解除我身上这诅咒的方法
Turns out, these curses were placed by black magic.
我只知道这是黑魔法造成的诅咒
But I could never find anyone who could wield black magic.
但我找不到会使用黑魔法的人
Until I crossed paths with that long-ears.
直到遇见那个长耳人
Black, I mean ancient magic comes in all sorts.
黑…古代魔法也有很多种
My research is mainly about drawing energy from another dimension--
我研究的主要是从异次元取出能量…
Don't give me that!
少糊弄我了！
I know you can do it!
我知道你办得到！
I mean, you've done it before!
毕竟你已经成功了！
You wielded black magic to create that eerie half-beast creature!
你施展了将人与魔物混合 使其变成怪物的黑魔法！
And you're all trekking through this dungeon
而且你们是为了 解除那女人身上的诅咒
to break the curse on that woman, right?
才会深入迷宫 对不对？
That means you know how to break curses!
这就表示你们知道 解除诅咒的方法嘛！
In that case, you can free me too!
那你们一定也可以解开我的诅咒！
Get rid of this beast's soul that's possessing me!
快驱除这头附在我身上的动物灵魂！
I'm sorry.
对不起
There's nothing I can do about that.
针对此事 我无能为力
What?
什么？
There's a lot we don't know about the soul.
我们对灵魂还有许多不明白的地方
But it's often likened to an egg.
但通常可以用鸡蛋来做比喻
Normally, it's nestled inside a shell we call flesh,
灵魂平常会待在肉体这层蛋壳里
but once the flesh is broken, the insides spill out
可是一旦肉体损伤 内容物就会漏出来
and can't be put back again.
而且再也无法装回壳里
This dungeon is under a spell
这座迷宫里被施了魔法
that forms a tough membrane beneath the shell,
会在蛋壳内侧产生一层坚固的膜
keeping the soul inside even when the body is damaged.
就算身体有损伤 灵魂也不会离开
At the moment, you and Falin have got two eggs inside one shell.
现在的你和法琳的状态 就像是一层蛋壳中有两颗蛋黄
And once mixed together,
灵魂一旦混合
those souls can never go back to their original form.
就无法恢复成原本的样子
I knew that, but hearing it laid out like that hits differently.
虽然我早就明白了 但实际听她这么一说感觉还是不一样
What?
什么？
If that's the case, why press on with your journey?
那你们为什么还要继续这趟旅程？
One reason is we can't just let my sister run wild.
第一个原因是我不能让妹妹 处在那种状态还撒手不管
She might kill the next adventurer she crosses paths with.
她可能会杀掉下一个遇上的冒险者
Or get herself killed by them.
也有可能反被杀掉
We want to do something before that happens.
在憾事发生前 我们希望能想办法解决
And if we return to the surface now,
而且如果我们现在回地表
we'll be apprehended for dabbling in black magic.
就会因为使用黑魔法而被抓起来
Shuro will likely tell the Lord of the Island about this incident.
修洛他应该会向岛主报告这件事
But…
怎么会…
Does this mean I'm stuck like this?
那我不就一辈子都只能这样了吗？
No, listen to me!
不 你听我说！
I know this might sound weird, but I'm honestly glad to have met you.
我知道这样讲有点奇怪 但我真心庆幸遇到了你
I'm not sure what kind of monster you're mixed with,
虽然我不知道 你是和哪种魔物混在一起
but your behavior is just like a human's.
但你的言行举止怎么看都是人类
And you're not out for blood either.
也没有表现出想杀人的冲动
So, maybe even Falin, once she's free from the dungeon's grip,
反过来说 只要法琳 没有受到迷宫的支配
might be able to reclaim her true self.
搞不好可以取回她本来的人格
Just realizing that makes me
光是能知道那一点
so very happy right now.
就让我现在非常开心
Here.
给你
Maybe things didn't unfold exactly as you'd hoped,
虽然和你的期待可能有点出入
but why not look at it from a positive angle,
但不妨想得正面点
like it was fate at work?
就当作是缘分如何？
The lord of the dungeon
这座迷宫的主人
is way more skilled with ancient magic than I am.
比我更精通怎么运用古代魔法
He might have some insights on how to separate souls.
说不定他会知道一些 和灵魂分离有关的知识
Hold up.
这是怎样？
Are you trying to recruit me?
难道是想拉我加入吗？
Either way, you can't make it back to the surface by yourself.
不管加不加入 你总没办法自己回地表吧
Was your name Asebi or something?
我记得你叫马醉木 是不是？
That's just the name I go by.
那是我的通称
Then…
那么…
It's Izutsumi.
莞苞
My name is Izutsumi.
我的名字是莞苞
Don't forget.
给我记好了
Laios, how much longer are you going to keep living like this?
莱欧斯 这种日子你打算过多久？
Father.
爸爸
It's about time you started living a proper life.
你也该开始过正常的生活了
I didn't let you go out there just so you could go off slaying dragons.
我让你出家门 不是为了让你去屠龙
Come back to the village!
快回村子！
But Falin's still…
可是法琳她还…
Forget about her.
忘了她吧
Do you really believe someone like you can make it out there
你以为凭你这种个性 可以在外头过得顺利吗？
when you ran away from both school and the army because you couldn't fit in?
不管是在学校还是军队都待不下去 最后只会逃避
You don't even have the knack for exploring the dungeon.
你也没有探索迷宫的才能
Just like back when you were gold-peeling,
只会像你以前做剥金者的那时候
your comrades will deceive you and take credit for your achievements.
被同伙给欺骗 抢走功劳
Because you're clueless when it comes to reading people.
因为你不懂怎么看人
It was the same with me.
你对我也是这样
You believed we were close friends,
你以为我是你的挚友
but I've always loathed--
但我一直都不擅长和你相处…
Would you let that go?
你很烦耶！
We've already talked it out.
那件事我们明明就吵完了
Wait, hang on.
不 等一下
Why are my parents here?
为什么我爸妈会在这里？
I haven't seen them in over a decade.
我已经超过十年没有见过他们了
And where am I?
话说回来 这里是哪里？
What was I up to?
我又在做什么来着？
I think I was…
我记得自己是在…
Lately, Marcille
最近的玛露希尔
seemed kind of worn out.
看起来好像挺累的
Marcille, we'll take care of keeping watch tonight.
玛露希尔 今天换我们守夜
You rest.
你就休息吧
Huh? But why?
什么？这是为何？
Don't worry about me.
不用管我啦
Come on. Just rest.
不用客气
Hey!
等一下！
Ugh, what are you doing?!
真是的 你是怎样啦？
I'm not that tired, you know.
我又没有很累
I'll be up in a bit.
我躺一下就会起来
I can't be the only one to…
不能只有我…
But before long, her quiet breathing turned into distressed groans.
但才过不久 她睡觉时的呼吸声 就变成了痛苦的呻吟声
What's the matter, Marcille?
你怎么了？玛露希尔
This isn't something to take lightly.
看起来不太妙
Is it a monster?
跟魔物有关吗？
Yeah, I think it's a Nightmare.
对 恐怕是梦魔
They prey on humans in their sleep, inflicting them with nightmares,
梦魔会附在睡着的人身上 害人做恶梦
and feed on their emotions.
并吸食其感情
If this goes on, Marcille will weaken and die.
再这样下去 玛露希尔会衰弱而死
Wake up, Marcille!
快起来 玛露希尔！
Don't. If you force her awake, you'll harm her soul.
住手 硬把她叫醒会伤到灵魂
When Shuro was possessed before, Falin entered his dreams to rescue him.
以前修洛被附身的时候 是法琳进到梦里去救他
Let's try that.
来试试那个办法吧
You're going to enter her dream?
你要进去玛露希尔的梦里？
Someone needs to help her realize she's dreaming.
得由某人让她察觉她在做梦
Use the dreamer as a pillow and…
把正在做梦的人当作枕头…
Right. I was trying to help Marcille.
对了 我是要来救玛露希尔
I'm inside my own dream!
我在自己的梦里！
The Nightmare got an easy bite out of me.
结果我中计了 被梦魔尝了一口
It's always like this.
每次都是这样
They sure know how to hit where it hurts!
对方真的很了解别人讨厌什么耶！
But now that I know it's just a dream, I've got the upper hand.
但只要发现是在梦里 就是我的天下
Come forth, my mightiest servant!
现身吧 我最强的仆从！
Now, I need to enter Marcille's dream.
现在需要进到玛露希尔的梦里
Since she's serving as my pillow right now,
现在她被压在我的头底下
I'll have to dig down.
这表示我只要把地面挖开 就可以过去了
This is the beauty of dreams.
这就是做梦的好处
This only works inside your own dream, though.
可惜只限在自己的梦里
That was a close one.
好险
That fall almost jolted me awake.
差点就因坠落而吓醒
So this is what Marcille's dream looks like.
这就是玛露希尔的梦境
Pretty cool.
好酷喔
Is someone there?
有人在吗？
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
This place is dangerous. You need to get out fast.
这里很危险 快逃呀
Marcille?
玛露希尔？
W-Who are you?
你是谁？
It's me, Laios!
是我 莱欧斯！
And we're inside your dream!
我们现在在你的梦里！
You need to wake up and…
所以你得赶快醒来…
A tremor?
在摇晃？
It's coming!
那家伙要来了
W-We need to run!
我们得快逃才行！
What's coming?
谁会来啊？
Just follow me!
不要问了 快过来！
It swallowed Papa and Pipi.
爸爸和皮皮都被那家伙吞掉了
Papa and Pipi?
“爸爸和皮皮”？
A dream about being chased, huh?
这是被某种东西追赶的恶梦啊
Those are pretty common, but nasty.
真是常见又讨人厌的梦呢
I remember Falin mentioning…
我记得法琳说过…
Nightmares thrive on emotional scars.
梦魔最爱人们内心的伤痛了
Stressful events and trauma.
会造成压力的事物 还有心理创伤
They trigger those memories and give people nightmares.
梦魔会刺激那些记忆 让人做恶梦
So all we have to do is shield their scars.
所以只要保护好内心的伤痛就可以了
I see.
是喔
But…
可是…
It's dangerous, so don't try it.
这很危险 不可以乱学喔
All right. I got it!
好 我知道了！
I'll take it down for you!
我去替你解决那家伙！
What are you doing? It's too risky!
你在做什么？很危险耶！
Don't worry.
不用怕
I might not seem like it, but I'm actually…
别看我这样 我可是相当…
What in the world is that?
那是什么鬼东西啦？
How should I know?
人家不知道啦！
Is that what Marcille's afraid of?
那就是玛露希尔的恐惧源头吗？
It's quite a bit over the top,
虽然好像被夸大了不少
but it does look like it'll be tough for me to take down.
但看来我是真的打不倒那家伙
It wouldn't be a threat if she realized this was all just a dream, though.
如果她本人能自觉到这是场梦 其实那就不会构成威胁
We've come far enough.
我们跑了这么远就没事了
Nowhere is safe.
没有地方是安全的
Nobody stands a chance against it.
没有人能抵抗
Don't worry.
你放心
Let's think of a way to take it down together.
我们一起想办法打倒敌人吧
What is Marcille afraid of?
玛露希尔会怕什么？
A monster, of course.
十之八九是魔物吧
It crawls sluggishly,
爬行的动作缓慢
has countless tentacles and an insatiable hunger,
有数不清的触手 食欲旺盛
and looks disgusting.
外表长得恶心
Is it some kind of insect?
是虫之类的吗？
But bugs that size are pretty rare.
可是那么巨大的虫也很少见
Bugs…
虫…
That's it!
对了！
It's a Wurm!
是蠕龙！
It's a Wurm from the Dragon family!
那是蠕龙 算是一种龙！
Its legs and eyes have degenerated, so it's more like a giant caterpillar.
脚和眼睛全都退化了 看起来就像只巨大的毛毛虫
It's voracious and devours anything living!
生性贪婪 只要是活的什么都吃！
It's weak to fire and light!
弱点是火和光！
Pretty classy choice!
这选择还真是硬派！
Huh?
什么？
When did it…
是什么时候…
Hold on!
抓紧了！
R-Run!
快跑啊
Did that thing touch you?
你被它碰到了吗？
Just a brush.
只是擦伤而已
Show me!
让我看看！
What's this?
这是怎样？
Damn.
糟了
I frightened her even more!
我害她吓到了！
It'll only make the Nightmare stronger.
这会让梦魔的力量变强
What a potent poison.
这毒也太强了
What happens if you die in someone else's dream?
万一在别人的梦里死掉会怎么样？
No, it wants us to feel anxious and scared.
不行 要是感到不安和恐惧 就会让梦魔称心如意
I have to lift Marcille's spirits.
要鼓励玛露希尔才行
Don't worry!
不用怕！
You can use magic!
你会用魔法！
You can take that thing down all by yourself!
靠你一个人就可以打倒那种家伙了！
Magic?
魔法？
The place is getting even more unstable.
环境变得更不安定了
Did I say something wrong?
难道我说错话了吗？
When…
是我…
When I tried to use magic to defeat it,
都是因为我施了魔法 想打倒那怪物
she ended up like this.
才会害她变成这样子
She?
“她”？
Wait, is that Falin?
这难道是法琳吗？
I get it now.
我懂了
Marcille feels guilty about Falin's transformation
玛露希尔后悔用了那招复活术
due to her resurrection magic.
害法琳变成那副模样
If she tried to defeat that thing, it means…
既然她说想打倒那怪物 就表示…
Marcille is afraid of death!
玛露希尔真正怕的是死亡！
I-It's coming back!
怪物又过来了！
Running won't solve anything.
你不可以一直逃跑
You have to face it head-on.
你需要去面对
What?
什么？
Don't worry. There's nothing for you to fear!
别担心 你完全没有必要害怕！
In the dungeon, even if you die, you can come back to life.
在这座迷宫里 就算死了还可以复活
Even Falin is still alive thanks to your resurrection magic.
也是因为你的复活术 才让法琳得以继续活着
And you're used to seeing corpses, right?
你不是连尸体都看惯了吗？
What?!
不会吧？
It's pulling me in!
要被吸进去了！
No!
不行！
It's only pulling me!
那家伙只会吸我！
Grab my hand!
快抓住我的手！
It's not poison.
这不是毒
I'm aging at an incredible rate.
是我正在急速变老
W-Wait a minute, Marcille.
等我一下 玛露希尔
I need to catch my breath.
我喘不过气
Something's not right.
事情不太对劲
Is there a creature capable of this?
有生物做得出这种事吗？
Maybe it's not even a creature at all.
搞不好不是生物
So you won't come along with me either?
你也不肯跟我一起走吗？
No, I can run again after a short rest.
不 我休息一下就可以继续跑了
You're lying!
你骗人！
Everyone who ran with me gave up, and they were all swallowed by that thing.
大家最后都会放弃跟我一起跑 然后被那怪物给吞掉
Papa, Pipi, Falin, everyone!
爸爸、皮皮、法琳 还有大家都一样！
That's why I studied a lot of magic.
所以我才会拼命学习魔法
But if that's what turned Falin into this,
但若是因此害法琳变成这样
I don't know what to do.
那我该怎么办才好？
Did your father pass away young?
你父亲很早就过世了啊？
At Papa's funeral, Mama told me
在爸爸的葬礼上 妈妈跟我说过
that I run faster than everyone else.
说我跑步的速度和大家都不一样
That I'd have to watch a lot of people go away.
我以后还得目送很多人离开
By the way, is Pipi a relative of yours?
顺便问一下 皮皮是你的亲戚吗？
Pipi's a bird.
是小鸟
I see.
我懂了
Marcille isn't afraid of death.
玛露希尔害怕的不是死亡
She's worried that those she cares about will pass away before her.
而是身边亲密的对象 会比自己还早死的不安
Marcille, calm down!
玛露希尔 冷静点！
If you're scared, it'll just empower that thing.
你越是害怕 它的力量只会越强！
But what am I supposed to do?
就算你这么说 我该如何是好？
I can't do anything!
我什么都做不到！
No, you can!
不 你做得到！
You're incredible, Marcille!
玛露希尔可是很厉害的！
I mean, just look at all these books!
你自己看 有这么多本书！
There was nothing like that in my dream!
我的梦里可是什么都没有！
You've been working tirelessly all this time!
你不是一直都很努力吗？
Don't lose heart. Have faith in yourself!
不要灰心 要对自己抱持信心！
You've got this, Marcille!
加油 玛露希尔！
No, get up!
不要 快站起来啦！
We have to run!
我们还是快逃啦！
And besides,
真要说的话
my magic isn't fully developed!
我的魔法还不完整！
If I had the same book he does,
如果有他手上那本书
I could use magic more effectively, but…
我就能将魔法驾驭得更完美
Then wish for it!
那就如此希望啊！
If you wish hard enough, you can accomplish anything!
只要你发自内心渴望 就做得到任何事！
Don't be afraid! You can do better next time!
不要怕 下次一定会做得更好！
Don't give up!
别放弃！
No!
不要
That's it, Marcille!
这就对了 玛露希尔！
Do it!
上吧！
That's how you use it?!
书是那样用的吗？
You're awake.
你醒了啊
You were both groaning in your sleep.
你们两个睡到一起呻吟耶
Are you okay?
还好吧？
I don't really remember.
我记得不是很清楚
It was an exhausting dream, though.
总觉得自己好像做了个很累的梦
She's falling back asleep!
她要睡回笼觉了！
No! Wake up, Marcille!
不行！快起来 玛露希尔！
My dream?
我的梦？
I don't remember much.
我不太记得了
But I think it was a fun one.
只觉得我好像做了个快乐的梦
Looks like it worked.
看来是成功了
Did something happen?
发生什么事了吗？
Pass me your pillow.
枕头借我一下
Huh?
嗯？
What are those?
那是什么？
Nightmares.
是梦魔
They hide in people's pillows and give them bad dreams.
这家伙会钻进人的枕头里 害人做恶梦
There are so many of them.
不过数量也太多了
They must have been nesting in your pillow for a while.
搞不好已经栖息在枕头里很久了
No way!
不会吧！
Senshi, are these edible?
先西 这能不能吃啊？
I've always been curious about their flavor.
我一直很好奇梦魔的味道
Yes, of course.
好 当然可以
First, let's clean the gunk off.
首先让它们吐杂质
If you soak them in hot water like this…
只要像这样用热水泡一阵子…
Nightmares, also known as Shen,
梦魔有个别名 叫做“蜃”
are actually related to Dragons.
其实是龙的同类
If you look closely, they're a bit Dragon-like.
仔细看看 是不是有点像龙？
You're kidding me.
你在开玩笑吧
Place the Nightmares in melted butter,
将梦魔平铺在融化的黄油上
add some wine, and cover with a lid.
加点葡萄酒 盖上锅盖
Finally, drizzle a bit of soy sauce over them,
最后再滴一点酱油
and it's done.
就完成了
What's this?
这是什么？
That's me!
是我耶！
The dream that the Nightmares devoured turned into a mirage.
被梦魔吃掉的梦变成海市蜃楼了
It's coming back to me.
我好像渐渐想起来了
Right,
没错
I was running from something
我本来是在逃离某物
when a dog appeared.
后来出现了一只狗
And we went on a treasure hunt together.
我就跟它一起去探险寻宝
It was such a fun dream!
那个梦好有趣喔！
The dog seems a bit scruffy.
这只狗好像有点脏耶
It looks dumb.
感觉没什么智商
What's wrong, Laios?
怎么了？莱欧斯
I remember it being a silver wolf, but…
我记得应该是只银白色的狼才对
Never mind.
算了
I'm glad if I helped in creating a fun dream for her.
若为这场快乐的梦有所贡献就好
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻译：柯欣冉